Inventory of the George Haven Putnam papers, circa 1800-1931
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
- PUBLISHED MATERIAL:
  - Periodicals:
    - The Outlook. March 25. "Prisoners of War," by George Haven Putnam. 3 copies., 3-25-? (Box 11)
    - The Outlook. Reprint, "The Defence of the Republic," by George Haven Putnam. (Box 11)
    - The Outlook. "Free Trader Will Surrender to Facts," by George Haven Putnam. (Box 11)
    - The Outlook. "The Speech that Won the East for Lincoln," by George Haven Putnam. (Box 11)
    - The Outlook. The Efficiency of Unions from an Employer's Standpoint," marked in pencil "J. B. Putnam.", 6-13-? (Box 11)
    - Oxford University Gazette. Clip of George Haven Putnam's oration upon conferment of the Honorary Degree of D. Litt. (Box 11)
    - The Nation. A Review of George Haven Putnam's book., 8-15-1912 (Box 11)
    - The National Tribune. Clip of review of George Haven Putnam's book. (Box 11)
    - The New York Times. "Would Extending the Ballot to Women Tend to Better City Government?" With comments by George Haven Putnam., 1-9-1910 (Box 11)
    - The New York Times. Clip. "George Haven Putnam Deadlines to Advance German Propoganda," including two letters., 1-31-1915 (Box 11)
    - The New York Times. Clip of letter by George Haven Putnam. (Box 11)
    - The New York Times. Clip of "Mr. A. C. Benson" Obituary., 6-17-1925 (Box 11)
    - The New York Times. Clip. "The Menace of Peace"., 12-5-1917 (Box 11)
    - North American Review. "Shall Women Practice Medicine?" (Box 11)
    - Public Ledger, Philadelphia. A review of George Haven Putnam's book., 10-7-1912 (Box 11)
    - Public Libraries, Vol. 16. No. 6., 6-1911 (Box 11)
    - Publisher and Ratailor (?). Vol. I, No. 9. "Commercial Morality," by George Haven Putnam., 4-1905 (Box 11)
    - The Publishers' Circular. "George Palmer Putnam.", 5-9-1903 (Box 11)
    - Publishers Weekly. Clip of untitled article about Theodore Roosevelt and G. P. Putnam's Sons., 1-11-1919 (Box 11)
    - Publishers Weekly. "Revision of the Book Tariff.", 12-1-1917 (Box 11)
    - Publishers Weekly. "International Copyright: G. H. Putnam's Letter to the London 'Standard.'" 4 copies., 3-11-1905 (Box 11)
    - Publishers Weekly. "A Historical Sketch of the Production and Distribution of Books and of the Librarian's Part Therein," by George Haven Putnam. 2 copies., 10-20-1917 (Box 11)
    - The Popular Science Monthly. "An Experiment in Primary Education," by Dr. Mary Putnam-Jacobi. (Box 11)
    - The Post Express. A review of George Haven Putnam's book., 8-17-1912 (Box 11)
    - Post Standard. Syracuse. "A Libby Prisoner," review of George Haven Putnam's book., 8-10-1912 (Box 11)
    - St. Louis Globe - Democrat. A review of George Haven Putnam's book., 9-29-1912 (Box 11)
    - Santa Fe New Mexican. "New Mexico Association on Indian Affairs Takes Issue With Action at Domingo; Statement of its Position.", 8-29-1923 (Box 11)
    - Santa Fe New Mexican. "Lenroot Bill Sentence of Death for Pueblos.", 9-22-1923 (Box 11)
    - Santa Fe New Mexican. "Wilson Reply to John Collier Makes Clear What Friends of Pueblo Indian Have Gained.", 10-18-1923 (Box 11)
    - The Sphere., 6-2-1906 (Box 11)
    - The Trend, Vol. I, No. 18. "Washington Irving," article mentions G. H. Putnam., 9-19-1925 (Box 11)
    - The World, New York. "Life and Voyages of Christopher Columbus," by Washington Irving., 9-18-1892 (Box 11)
    - 38 pieces, unidentified. (Box 11)
- SCRAPBOOKS:
  - Accounts dating back to 1800. No covers. (Box 11)
  - Addresses and Comments. #'s 1,2,3,4,5. (Box 11)
  - The Case Against Germany, World War I. Envelopes I, II, and III. (Box 13)
  - Correspondences - Putnam Publications. Approximately 65 pieces, including letters from Margret Armstrong, M. and B. Booth, George P. Duniap, Branson Howard, Thomas Spencer Jerome, Ellen Hoy, Dorothy Mills, M. M. Riplly, Edward N. A. Seligman, and a few others., 4-1-1924 (Box 13)
  - 80th Birthday Greetings, to George Haven Putnam. Approximately 150 pieces. All sent the first of April, 1924 (April 2 was George Haven Putnam's birthday). Including from Edwin Lefevre, Ernest Howe, William T. Manning, William Beebe, Publishers' Lunch Club, Yale Club, John B. Caldwell, Walter Gordan Merriet, New york Employing Printers Assn., Elihu Root, Lyman Boocher Stowe, The English Speaking Union of the United States, Henry Holt, William Emerson, J. H. Sears, and others. Also, newspaper clippings., 1-17-1873 (Box 13)
  - Letters and Articles: (Box 13)
    - Page 3. From Bayard Taylor to Haven., 1-17-1873 (Box 13)
    - Page 3. From Bayard Taylor to Haven., 1-17-1875 (Box 13)
    - Page 3. From Charles S. Palmer to George H. Putnam., 7-20-1896 (Box 13)
    - Page 3. From G. P. Putnam to Dr. Bullard. (Box 13)
    - Page 5. Envelope containing a lock of hair from Lit_ _ney, born May 13, 1869, died Oct. 13, 1871., circa 1869-1871 (Box 13)
    - Page 38. From A. R. MacDonough to George H. Putnam., 12-20-1872 (Box 13)
    - Page 38. From Henry Holt to Mrs. Putnam., 1-9-1873 (Box 13)
    - Page 44. Obituaries of George P. Putnam, newspaper clippings. (Box 13)
    - Page 45. Harper's Weekly, "George P. Putnam," obituary. (Box 13)
    - Page 47. Memorandum to the Putnam family from Henry Holt and Andrew Armstrong. (Box 13)
    - Page 48-52. Several more clippings of George P. Putnam's obituaries. (Box 13)
    - Page 59. From H. S. Field to Mrs. Putnam. (Box 13)
    - Page 62. From Wm. Ingraham Kip. Bishop of California. (Box 13)
    - Page 70. From P. A. Chasbourne to George Haven Putnam., 1-8-1872 (Box 13)
    - Page 70. 1872, Dec. 21. From S. B. Bridjman to Haven Putnam., 12-21-1872 (Box 13)
    - Page 71. 1873, Jan. 20. From Susan Fenimore Cooper., 1-20-1873 (Box 13)
    - Page 80. From Little Brown and Co. to G. P. Putnam's Sons., 12-30-1972 (Box 13)
    - Page 83. Obituary clipping of Mrs. Isaac T. Smith. (Box 13)
    - Page 85. Engraving of Major Gen. Israel Putnam. (Box 13)
    - Page 86. Engraving; Putnam's Escape at Horse Neck. (Box 13)
    - Page 87. Engravings; Putnam Receiving the News of the Battle of Lexington. Genl. Putnam's Feat at Horse Neck, Genl. Putnam's Escape from the British at Horse-neck. (Box 13)
    - Page 96. Two clippings concerning Mary Putnam Jacobi. (Box 13)
    - Page 100. Obituary, newspaper clipping, "Mrs. John Bishop." (Box 13)
    - Page 103. From Arabella Rawson Carter to George Haven Putnam. (Box 13)
    - Page 104. Rowayton Petition. (Box 13)
    - Page 116. Certificate, Ordre National de La Legion d'Honneur, to George Putnam., 7-21-1891 (Box 13)
    - Page 123. From Alice Walker to George Haven Putnam., 11-11-1891 (Box 13)
    - Page 126. From R. Pearsall Smith to George Haven Putnam., 6-18-1891 (Box 13)
    - Page 129. Certificate of Holy Matrimony of George Haven Putnam and Rebecca Rattelle Shepard., 7-7-1889 (Box 13)
    - Page 132. Typed copy of genealogical information of Caroline P. Putnam, mother of George P. Putnam. (Box 13)
    - Page 133. Newspaper clipping, obituary of Douglas Putnam. (Box 13)
    - Page 136. Telegram announcing Bowdain College conferring Master of Arts degree upon George Haven Putnam., 6-28-1894 (Box 13)
    - Page 138. From R. P. Putnam to Mrs. H. G. Nott., 9-7-1859 (Box 13)
    - Page 140. Troy Daily Times, Obituary clipping, "Death of Rev. Dr. Tyler.", 1-18-1896 (Box 13)
    - Page 141. "The Homes and Haunts of Israel Putnam," by William Farrand Livingston. (Box 13)
    - Page 145. Photograph of Poster, "Republican Association - The Citizens of Yonkers and Vicinity Opposed to the Extension of Slavery…" with G. P. Putnam's name at the bottom. (Box 13)
    - Page 147. Typed copy, "Response of S. H. Church on the bestowment of Honorary degree of Lieu. B. on George Haven Putnam, by the Western University of Pennc. At Commencement at Carnegie Music Hall, Pittsburgh., 6-9-1898 (Box 13)
    - Page 151. Six Clippings concerning Herbert Putnam, appointed Librarian of Congress by President McKinley. (Box 13)
    - Page 152. Three clippings announcing George Haven Putnam's engagement to Emily James Smith, two from the World., 2-20-1898 (Box 13)
    - Page 154. Typed, partial copy of Victorine Haven's family tree. (Box 13)
    - Page 159. Newspaper clippings; "Mrs. Grace Thacer Putnam," obituary, the American Stationer, "Mr. Putnam and the District Attorney.", 3-24-? (Box 13)
    - Page 161. From George Haven Putnam to Covo. Dunlap., 12-27-1857 (Box 13)
    - Page 175. Newspaper clipping, "Isaac Townsend Smith Dead." (Box 13)
    - Page 178. From Mary R. Graves to George Haven Putnam., 2-19-1906 (Box 13)
    - Page 179. The Reading Chronicle. "Early Ministers of the North Precinct and Some of Their Descendants.", 2-2-1906 (Box 13)
    - Page 190. Genealogy of the Descendants of Richard Haven of Lynn, Mass. Typed copy., 3-3-1911 (Box 13)
    - Page 192. Newspaper clipping, obituary of Mrs. Anna Smith Loring. (Box 13)
    - Page 199. Engravings of David Putnam and Douglas Putnam., 1803 (Box 13)
    - Page 200. Extract from the Haven Geneology. Compiled by Josiah Adams of Framingham, Mass. Typed., 1844 (Box 13)
    - Page 203. Boston Evening Transcript. "Mrs. Joseph Lindon Smith Recieves Cross of the Legion of Honor for War Services.", 4-2-1921 (Box 13)
  - Firm History, Vols. I and III, G. P. Putnam and Co. Mostly newspaper clippings of reviews, some letters. (Box 13)
  - Grand Jury. Mostly newspaper clippings. A few letters, including from C. H. Parkhurst, Theodore Roosevelt, George Barclay Moffar, James H. Canfield, and others., 3-?-1900 (Box 13)
  - Managers Meeting Minutes, G. P. Putnam's Sons., 5-2-1898 (Box 13)
  - Minutes - Publishing Board. G. P. Putnam's Sons., 7-29-1925 to 9-30-1926 (Box 13)
  - Municipal and Good Government. Copies of George Haven Putnam's letters, including those to Joseph M. Price, The President of the Citizen's Union, George B. Moffet, McClure's Magazine, Gen. Wager Swayne, The New York Sun, The New York Journal, and others., 4-15-1894 to 10-21-1901 (Box 13)
  - Publisher's Articles, Vols. I, II, III, IV, and V. Clippings. (Box 13)
- MISCELLANEOUS:
  - The American Rights League. Leaflet, "A Declaration of Principles by American Citizens." (Box 12)
  - Authors of New York. A list of 4 pages. (Box 12)
  - The American Committee Instituted to Give Cooperation in the Establishment in the University of London, at University College, of a Chair for Instruction in American History. Several items, including a postcard from Sir Geoffrey Butler, Vote of Executive Council, American Historical Association, Subscriptions, 55 pages. 48 other pieces, including letters, newspaper clippings, lists., 12-28-1926 (Box 12)
  - Biography. Typed copy of Dr. Mary Putnam Jacobi's Life. (Box 12)
  - Biography. John Bigelow, 92 pages, typed, of his life. (Box 12)
  - Brooke-Bright Foundation. Lectures., 1928-1929 (Box 12)
  - "George Canning, a Diplomatic View." Handwritten Manuscript by I. I. Dillon., 1823 (Box 12)
  - Certificate of Sydow, copy, handwritten, 1 page. (Box 12)
  - Document. By George III, concerning William Hunter., 1783 (Box 12)
  - Invitation to George Haven Putnam to the Sir George Watson Chair of American History, Literature, and _. (Box 12)
  - Invitation to the Putnams to Memorial to Capt. Charles Fryatt., 10-2-1919 (Box 12)
  - Introduction speech for George Haven Putnam by Oxford University, on the bestowal of Doctor of Letters. (Box 12)
  - Washington Irving. Several pieces, including the Authors Club program for Washington Irving Evening, 1914; Memorandum of property of Washington Irving, drawn up 1857; Legal papers, 4 agreement, 57 copyrights., 8-10-1857 and 4-8-1914 (Box 12)
  - Letters to G. P. Putnam from Revenue Office. 4 pieces., 1862 (Box 12)
  - Notification of election to the Athenaeum club., 3-2-1926 (Box 12)
  - Outlines for proposed books by Frederick S. Dellenbaugh, submitted G. P. Putnam's Sons. 8 pieces. (Box 12)
  - Open letter "To the publishers of the United States concerned with copyright productions, or who are, on any grounds, interested in international relations." By George Haven Putnam., 2-12-1913 (Box 12)
  - Photographs. Mrs. Beatrice Harraden, 2 pictures. 1 simulated photograph of the Knickerbocker Press. 3"x4". (Box 12)
  - Poem. "To Catherine," by Rev. Joseph Dennie Tyler. (Box 12)
  - Political leaflet, New York, with cartoon., 1876 (Box 12)
  - Poster. "Fourth of July, 1918." Extracts from Tennyson and Whittier poems concerning the relationship between England and America., 7-4-1918 (Box 12)
  - Programs. The Economic Club of Brockton; The Economic Club of Boston; Lincoln Centenary, held in 46 public schools of New York; 19th Army Corps 28th Annual meeting and dinner., 4-25-1916; 4-26-1916; 2-12-1909; 10-19-1914 (Box 12)
  - Publisher's Lunch Club. 2 copies of their constitution. (Box 12)
  - Review. "Peace and Justice Throughout the World," by George Haven Putnam, reviewed for The Churchman by Mrs. James V. Chalmers. Typed copy. 2 pages. (Box 12)
  - Subcommittee of the Senate Committee on the Indian Affairs. Itinerary., 4-13-1931 to 5-22-1931 (Box 12)